A Guide to the John Lesh Jacobs papers FA1273
Rockefeller Archive Center
John Lesh Jacobs papers, Accession 2014:025
1931-1941
Rockefeller Archive Center
Jacobs, John Lesh, Dr.
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
Landsteiner, Karl
FA1273
3.33 Cubic Feet 2 standard record storage boxes, and one oversize box.
Arrangement
Arranged as received.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated to the Rockefeller Archive Center in 2014 by the family of Dr. Jacobs.
Scope and Contents
Primarily contains reprints, articles and biographical material.
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Jacobs worked with Karl Landsteiner at the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research/Rockefeller University.
- Reprint: "Cutaneous hypersensitivity to Iodine" by John L. Jacobs and Abraham colmes (Box 1)
- Reprint: "Serological Reactions of Azoprotiens Derived from Aromatic Hydrocarbons and diaryl Compounds" by John Jacobs (Box 1)
- Reprint: "The Specificity of Formalized Protiens" by John L. Jacobs and Sheldon C Sommers (Box 1)
- Reprint:On the Use of Adsorbents in Immunizations with Haptens" by John Jacobs (Box 1)
- Reprint: "Sensitization of Guinea pigs with Mathyl Heptine Corbonate" by Karl Landsteiner and Justin Jacobs (Box 1)
- Reprint: " II. Experiments on Immunization with Haptens" by Karl Landsteiner and John Jacobs (Box 1)
- Reprint: "Experiments on Sensitization of Guinea Pigs with Simple Chemical Compounds" by Karl Landsteiner and John Jacobs (Box 1)
- Reprint: "Studies on the Sensitization of Animals with Simple Chemical Compounds " Parts I, II, III, VI, VII by Karl Landsteiner and John L Jacobs (Box 1)
- Reprint: "Experiments on Sensitization of Guinea Pigs with Simple Chemical Compounds" by Karl Landsteiner and John Jacobs (Box 1)
- Reprint: "Supplementary Note on Skin sensitization with Simple Chemical Compounds" by Karl Landsteiner and John Jacobs (Box 1)
- Reprint: "II. Experiments on Immunization with Haptens" by Karl Landsteiner and John Jacobs (Box 1)
- Reprint: "Immunization Experiments with Lecithtin" by P.A. Levene, Karl Landsteiner and J. Van Der Scheer (Box 1)
- Reprint: "Experiments on Anaphylaxis to Azoproteins-Third Paper" by Karl Landsteiner and Philip Levine (Box 1)
- Reprint: "Immunochemistry" by Merill W. Chase and Karl Landsteiner (Box 1)
- "Suggestions for the Preporation of Manuscripts"- The Journal of Experimental Medicine (Box 1)
- Reprint: "Die Blutgruppen und Ihre Praktische Anwendung Besonders Fur die Bluttransfusion" by Karl Landsteiner (Box 1)
- Reprint: [in cyrillic alphabet] (Box 1)
- The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, 1936 (Box 1)
- Report: "A Report on the Immundogy of Iodo-proteins" by John L. Jacobs (Box 1)
- Erlenmeyer Paper (Box 1)
- Dihydro-cholesterm, 1931-1932 (Box 1)
- Henderson-Anderson (Box 1)
- Article-"She Will Understand"-by Dr. Thornwell Jacobs (Box 1)
- "Eczema of the Upper Orbit"-John L. Jacobs (Box 1)
- "Relationships Between Immediate and Delayed Skin Reactions" John L Jacobs (Box 1)
- Paper- J.G.M.A. asthma- non-specific factors inducing (Box 1)
- Reprint: "The Specificity of Formalized Protiens" by John L. Jacobs and Sheldon C Sommers, 1939 (Box 1)
- Letter Treasure (Box 1)
- VII Strength of Soluion by Patch Scratch, Intracutaneous Methods E Citraconic Anhydride, use VI Pigs (Box 1)
- VI Relation Between Immediate and Delayed Reaction e Citraconic Anhydride (Box 1)
- V Specificity of Animals sensitized to Maleic and Acetic Anyhydride (Box 1)
- Acrolein Specificity- Sensitization to Acrolein and Specificity e Formaldehyde (Box 1)
- Notes: Specificity and Chlorides (Box 1)
- II Specificty to Maleic and Acetic Anyhydride (Box 1)
- Reprint: "Immediate Reactions to Anhydrides of Wheal-and-Erythema Type" J.L. Jacobs, T. S. Golden and J. J. Kelley, 1940 (Box 1)
- Reprint-"Cutaneous Hypersensitivity to Iodine"- John L.Jacobs and Abraham Colmes, 1940 (Box 1)
- Reprint: "Complement-Fixation Tests on Rabbits with Brown-Pearce Carcinoma"- J.L. Jacobs and J. D. Houghton, 1941 (Box 1)
- Reprint: "A Method of Training Guinea Pigs for hypersensitiveness to Rhus Toxicodron" by J.L. Jacobs and M.L. Welcker, 1938 (Box 1)
- Reprint: "Immediate Generalized Skin Reactions in Hyper-Sensitive Guinea Pigs" by John L. Jacobs, 1940 (Box 1)
- Manuscript: "Heredity Predisposition to Sensitization in Guinea Pigs"- J. L Jacobs, J.J. Kelley and S.C. Sommers (Box 1)
- Bound Reprint (Box 2)
- Bound Reprint (Box 2)
- Bound Reprint (Box 2)
- The American Academy of Allergy Member Certificate, 2014:025:001 (Box 3)
- Harvard Diploma (BS), 2014:025:002 (Box 3)
- The Alpha Omega Alpha Membership Certificate, 2014:025:003 (Box 3)
- Harvard Medical School Diploma, 2014:025:004 (Box 3)